Guide to the Guido Kisch papers, [ca. 1934-1972].
Kisch, Guido papers
- "The Rights and Immunities of the Minority" by Irving A. Agus, October 1954 (Box 1, Folder 240)
- Assorted Reviews in "Jüdische Sozialarbeit", February 7, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 241)
- Friendly Corrspondence Between Irving A. Agus and Kisch, Summer 1967 (Box 1, Folder 242)
- Kisch's "Das Breslauer Seminar", 1969 (Box 1, Folder 243)
- "Jüdische Klassiker der Deutschen Rechtswissenschaft" and related Correspondence, 1938-1955 (Box 1, Folder 244)
- Correspondence with and Papers related to Monika Richarz, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 245)
- Papers relating to Arthur and Marcus Cohn, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 246)
- Casual Correspondence with Alexander Marx, August-September 1950 (Box 1, Folder 247)
- Assorted Cards with Citation Information (Box 1, Folder 248)
- Correspondence with Berkeley and related Papers, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 249)
- Correspondence with E.G. Lowenthal, May-June 1971 (Box 1, Folder 250)
- Eva G. Reichmann's Thoughts on Her 80th Birthday and related Papers, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 251)
- Correspondence Between Jacob J. Rabinowitz and Kisch, as well as Rabinowitz's "Some Remarks on the Evasion of the Usury Laws in the Middle Ages", 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 252)
- Assorted Receipts and Programs, 1954-1967 (Box 1, Folder 253)
- Book of Grace and Blessings from Wedding Reception of Victoria Daubert and Arnold Kisch, July 16, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 254)
- "Ein Tiroler Fayence-Often" by Günther Schiedlausky, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 255)
- Ellis Rivkin's Review of "The Jews and Modern Capitalism" by Werner Sombart, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 256)
- Correspondence over Kisch's Pamphlet on the "Yellow Badge in History", March-April 1942 (Box 1, Folder 257)
- Papers Related to Eleonore Sterling, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 258)
- Correspondence with Librarian in Berlin, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 259)
- Correspondence on Upcoming Book, January 12, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 260)
- Correspondence, February 9, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 261)
- Assorted Papers related to Jewish Marital Practices, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 262)
- Thank-you Letter from Kisch to Alfred Gottschalk for "Hrebrew Union College - Jewishh Institute of Religion: At One Hundred Years", June 8, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 263)
- "England für ein Jüdisches Nationalheim in Palästina - vor hundert Jahren", 1939 (Box 1, Folder 264)
- Notes on European History (Box 1, Folder 265)
- "Correspondence with Israelitische Kultusgemeinde Znaim", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 266)
- Correspondences with Aufbau, 1946-1956 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondences with Keyser, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondences, 1951-1957 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondences with Ruck, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondences, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ephemerals, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with Michel Villey, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with Anglo-Federal Banking Corp, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence with Fanetti, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence with K. Steinberg, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence with Societe Histoire du Droit et des Institutions, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence with A.N. Marquis Co., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Correspondence with American Jewish Archives, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence with Mrs. Frank Bishop, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Correspondence with Gmur, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Correspondence with Raphael Loewe, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence with Millstone, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Correspondence with North-American Continental Co., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Correspondence with Andreas Staehelin, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Correspondence with Sterling, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Correspondence with Stephen Barber, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Correspondence with Arnold Ehrhardt, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Correspondence with Gereuig, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Correspondence with Lothar Rothschild, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Correspondence with Joseph Babad, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Correspondence with Adelbert Erler, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Correspondence with Fikeutscher, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Correspondence with Louis Ginsberg, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Correspondence with Alfred Karger, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Correspondence with Berthold Rosenthal, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Correspondence with Esther Rawidowicz, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Photocopy with Abbreviations (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Correspondence, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Correspondence with Berger, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Newsletter B'nai B'rith, November 1956 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Correspondence with Brandeis University, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Correspondence with E.J. Cohn, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Correspondence with Günther Christian Hamann, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Minutes - Joseph Popper Lodge B'nai B'rith, November 17, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Correspondence with Meyers, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Correspondence Monumenta Germaniae Historica, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Correspondence with Philosophische Fakultat der Universitut Hamburg, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Correspondence with Reform Congregation Keneseth Israel, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Correspondence with I. Reich, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Correspondence with Riccobouo, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Correspondence with Gerhard Ritter, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Correspondence with Calasso, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Correspondence with the Department of State, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Correspondence with Louis Finkelstein, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Correspondence with George C. Miles, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Correspondence with Israel H. Levinthal, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Correspondence with Ernest J. Lewy, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Correspondence with Library of Congress, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Correspondence with Harry Schneiderman, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Correspondence with Abraham I. Shinedling, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Correspondence with E. J. Bruno Weil, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Correspondence, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Correspondence with W. F. ALbright, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Correspondence with Berger, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Correspondence with Elbert H. Gary Library, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Correspondence with Lauger, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Correspondence with Elbert L. Sapinsley, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Correspondence with Leo Shick, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Correspondence with Josef Shülzle, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Clippings, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 75)
- Ephemeral, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Congregation Beth Hillel, November-December 1955 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Correspondence, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Correspondence with Brandeis, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- Correspondence with Joseph Popper Lodge, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Manuscript on Jewish History (Box 2, Folder 81)
- Manuscript-Related Papers (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Manuscript-Related Papers (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Manuscript: Anti-Semitism in Germany (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Manuscripto n Anti-Semitism (Box 2, Folder 85)
- Lecture Notes on Discrimination (Box 2, Folder 86)
- Notes (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Notes on the Codex Theodosianus (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Writing: "Ghetto" (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Writings "Ghetto" (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Jewish Population (Box 2, Folder 91)
- Magazine "Congress Weekly, December 11, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- Magazine "B'nai B'rith", August-September 1937 (Box 2, Folder 93)
- "Jewish Names" (Box 2, Folder 94)
- Notes on "Hebrew Union College" (Box 2, Folder 95)
- Clippings (Box 2, Folder 96)
- Notes: Jewish Life in the Medieval World (Box 2, Folder 97)
- "Protocols of the Elders of Zion" (Box 2, Folder 98)
- Notes about the Ghetto (Box 2, Folder 99)
- Some Important Dates of Medieval History (Box 2, Folder 100)
- M. H. L. Examination in European History (Box 2, Folder 101)
- History Seminar for Graduate Students (Box 2, Folder 102)
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- Correspondence, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 103)
- Correspondence with Jerome Spivack, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 104)
- Correspondence with Taxon, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 105)
- Correspondence with Congregation B'nai B'rith, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- Correspondence with Hebrew Union College, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 107)
- History Examiniation Book for Marshall Hurwitz, April 1953 (Box 2, Folder 108)
- Reports by Tepfer and Orlinsky on Dissertations, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 109)
- Notes (Box 2, Folder 110)
- Report on Thesis on Rashi the Educator (Box 2, Folder 111)
- Report on Leon Kronish's Thesis (Box 2, Folder 112)
- Reports on Theses, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 113)
- Report on Augustus Loeb's Thesis, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 114)
- Report on E. Budick's Thesis, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 115)
- Report on Levis Satlow's Thesis, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 116)
- Correspondence with Judah J. Seidler, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 117)
- Report on Meyer Greenberg's Thesis, 944 (Box 2, Folder 118)
- Report on Elihu Shagrin's Thesis, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 119)
- Report on Jordan I. Taxon's Thesis, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 120)
- Correspondence with Bell, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 121)
- Report on Paul Siegel's Thesis, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 122)
- Report on Jerome M. Pines' Thesis, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 123)
- Report on Sanford Jarashow's Thesis, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 124)
- Report on Joseph M. Reich's Thesis, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 125)
- Report on Bernhard N. Cohn's Thesis, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 126)
- Report on Andrew J. Robins' Thesis, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 127)
- Correspondence with the Jewish Institute of Religion, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 128)
- Correspondence with Hebrew Union College, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 129)
- Manuscript for "The Jews of Austria" (Box 2, Folder 130)
- Student Report for History IV, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 131)
- Manuscript for "History of the Jews - Middle Ages" (Box 2, Folder 132)
- Manuscript for "History of the Jews - Middle Ages" (Box 2, Folder 133)
- Manuscript for "History of the Jews - Middle Ages" (Box 2, Folder 134)
- Manuscript for "History of the Jews - Middle Ages" (Box 2, Folder 135)
- Syllabus for "History of the Jews", 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 136)
- Notes, Oversized (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Paper on Religious Movements (Box 2, Folder 138)
- Outline History, Oversized (Box 2, Folder 139)
- "History III" Papers (Box 2, Folder 140)
- "A Treatise on Religious Power and Judaism" by Rabbi Moses Mendelssohn (1782), Trans. from German by Isaac Leeser (Box 2, Folder 141)
- Notes on Jewish History (Box 2, Folder 142)
- History Class Notes, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 143)
- Wilhelm, 1671, Oversized (Box 2, Folder 144)
- History Notes, Oversized (Box 2, Folder 145)
- Outline - Prussian State and the Jews (Box 2, Folder 146)
- Outline - Prussian State and the Jews (Box 2, Folder 147)
- Outline - Jews of Austria (Box 2, Folder 148)
- Jewish Policy and Legislation - Kaiser (Box 2, Folder 149)
- Prussian state and the Jews (Box 2, Folder 150)
- Lecture Notes, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 151)
- Thesis Outline for Assorted Graduate Students (Box 2, Folder 152)
- Reports on Theses, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 153)
- Correspondence with George Ende, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 154)
- Class Schedule Fall Term 1951, 1951; Oversized (Box 2, Folder 155)
- Invitation from the Menorah School of Adult Education, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 156)
- Correspondence with Jewish Institute of Religion, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 157)
- Correspondence with Gertrude Adelstein, 1949-1952 (Box 2, Folder 158)
- Correspondence with Jewish Institute of Religion, 1940-1941 (Box 2, Folder 159)
- Correspondence with Jewish Institute of Religion, 1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 160)
- Student Records, 1938, Oversized (Box 2, Folder 161)
- Class Records, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 162)
- Class Records, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 163)
- Clss Records, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 164)
- Class Records, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 165)
- Class Records, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 166)
- Class Records, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 167)
- Class Records, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 168)
- Class Records, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 169)
- Report on Bernhard N. Cohn's Thesis, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 170)
- Correspondence with Bernhard Cohn, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 171)
- Correspondence with Bureau of Jewish Education, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 172)
- Thesis Requirements, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 173)
- Correspondence with Ludwig Aron, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 174)
- Correspondence with Harold L. Gelfman, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 175)
- Correspondence with Arthur Chiel, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 176)
- Correspondence with Nelson Glueck about Soltes, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 177)
- Requirements for Doctorate (Box 2, Folder 178)
- Correspondence with Henry Slonimsky, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 179)
- Correspondence with Leo Shubow, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 180)
- Correspondence with Abraham Krantz, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 181)
- Correspondence with Bernard Perelmuter, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 182)
- Correspondence with Alvan Rubin, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 183)
- Correspondence with Henry Orlinsky about Samuel Freilich and between Freilich and Kisch, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 184)
- Correspondence with Joseph B. Messing, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 185)
- Personalia, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 186)
- Christmas Cards Blackwell, 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 187)
- Subscriptions for Historica Judaica, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 188)
- Cards, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 189)
- Correspondence, 1941-1956 (Box 2, Folder 190)
- Correspondence with H. W. Janson, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 191)
- Correspondence with Princeton University, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 192)
- Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 193)
- Correspondence, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 194)
- Correspondence with Fred Ascher, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 195)
- Correspondence with Berger, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 196)
- Correspondence with Rudolf Heilbrun, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 197)
- Correspondence with Siegfried Guggenheim, 1955-1956 (Box 2, Folder 198)
- Correspondence with the Jewish Institute of Religion, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 199)
- Correspondence with Jewish Theological Society of America, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 200)
- Correspondence with Joseph Popper Lodge, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 201)
- Correspondence with Frederick S. Knobloch, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 202)
- Correspondence with Queen's College, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 203)
- Correspondence with Joseph W. Wissenberg, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 204)
- Correspondence with the Jewish Center Lecture Bureau, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 205)
- Correspondence with B. Beinart, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 206)
- Correspondence with Edgar E. Siskin, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 207)
- Postcard from Lago Maggiore, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 208)
- Clippings related to Jewish History (Box 2, Folder 209)
- Manuscript about Gabriel Riesser and Jewish Emancipation (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Manuscript on Jewish History of the 18th and 19th Centuries (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Manuscript on Jewish Trade History and the Jewish Policy in Prussia of the 18th Century (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Manuscript on 18th Century Jewish Economic History (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Manuscript on Samuel Oppenheimer (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Manuscripts on Jewish History from the 17th through 19th Centuries (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Manuscript on Jewish Emancipation in 18th and 19th Centuries (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Correspondence with Victor Reis, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Paper on Jewish Chronology by Victor Reis, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Manuscript on Jewish Legal Situation in the 18th Century (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Manuscript on Jewish Emancipation since the 17th Century (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Manuscript on European Jewish History of the 19th Century (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Manuscript on Jewish Emancipation History since the 18th Century (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Manuscript on Jewish Demographic Data since the 17th Century (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Manuscript on "The Method of Presenting the Jewish History from 1815-1880" (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Manuscript on "The Emancipation of the Jews in Germany; In Particular the Prussian Jewry-edict of 1812" (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Manuscript on "The Struggle for Reform of the Jewish Status in Germany up to the Year 1806" (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Manuscript on "The Passing Emancipation in the Province of French Command in German Territory" (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Manuscript on "Survey of the Jewish Status in the Rest of the States of the German Federation During the Period of Reaction" (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Manuscript on "The New Struggle for Equality in Germany; in Particular the Work of Gabriel Riesser" (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Manuscript on the "Prussian Law of July 23rd, 1847, Regarding Jewish Relations" (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Manuscript on "The Emancipation of the Jews in France by the Revolution, and during the Empire" (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Manuscript on "The Jewish Emancipation in France as seen in the light of the French concept of Nation" (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Manuscript on "The Effect of the Emancipation upon the Jews of France Socially and Economically" (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Manuscript on "The Intellectual Struggle for Reform in Germany (1832-1843) (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Notes on Rabbinic Tradition (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Comprehensive Exam for European History, Spring 1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Correspondence Related to Books on Antisemitism, June 23, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Paper on Ludwig der Fromme (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Paper on Ludwig the Pious and Other Religious Figures (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Saul M. Diamant's M.A. Thesis: "The Attitude of the Churches in Germany toward the Nazi Persecution of the Jews", 1959 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Report on Thesis of Saul M. Diament, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Hebrew Union College Bulletin, October 1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Courses of Dr. Kisch, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Papers for History Examinations (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Paper on American Jewish History (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Correspondence and Papers Concerning Antisemitism (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Papers from Kisch's History Courses (Box 3, Folder 38)
- "The Jews Under the King's Peace" (Box 3, Folder 39)
- "The Medieval Conception of the Jew", 1945 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Graduate Class, 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Selected Sources on Jewish History (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Notes for Jewish History Courses (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Chronological Survey from 1492-1789, along with Notes for Kisch's History Courses (Box 3, Folder 44)
- "The Church and the Jews" by George LaPiana in "Historica Judaica", October 1949 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Writings on 15th and 16th Century Jewish-Christian Relations (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Wiring by David Reubeni and Salomo Molcho on Messianic History in the 17th Century (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Writings on Jewish European History in the 16th and 17th Century (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Papers from Kisch's History Course, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 49)